Experience

Web Developer

June 2022 — Current | 5874 Commerce

At 5874 Commerce, I work on the BigCommerce platform, building and maintaining e-commerce websites for a variety of clients. I work on a variety of frontend-focused tasks, using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript most often, but I also work with React and TypeScript on various projects. I work closely with designers and project managers to ensure that projects are delivered on-time and to the exact specification. Writing code quickly and efficiently is essential, as is clear, effective communication.

Frontend Developer January 2022 - May 2022 | Distinction

At Distinction, I worked on a variety of frontend projects, from building simple, vanilla JS sign-up forms to creating reusable, responsive site components with Vue.

Because of the range of projects, learning new platforms and tools quickly was essential, as was a practical, solution-focused attitude to writing code.

Junior Software Developer March 2021 – January 2022 | MyBalance

I was responsible for designing and developing the MyBalance website using React and Next; I designed and built the site's blog feature, using Next's server-side capabilities; I incorporated Firebase analytics into the site, providing detailed reports on user behaviour; I designed and built article search functionality with Fuse.js.

Note

In addition to the above software roles, I have a variety of experience in publishing, education, and the service industry. For the sake of brevity, I haven't included those roles here.

Rhys Jenkins

Mobile: 07577 627 643

Email: 89rhysjenkins@gmail.com

Summary

I am a diligent, creative web developer with over two years of experience working with some of the most popular frontend frameworks and platforms.

I'm most comfortable with React and TypeScript, but my fundamental HTML, CSS, and JavaScript skills are strong, and I'm confident working with both the BigCommerce and WordPress platforms.

What's more, I have a practical, can-do attitude to software development, and I'm keen to move into a role in which I can continue to learn new skills and technologies.

Technologies

ReactTypeScript

NextJavaScript

• HTML • CSS

SassTailwind

Bootstrap
 BigCommerce

• WordPress • Git

Skills

Responsive designUX

Debugging
 Refactoring

• Writing • Communication

Education

University of Salford, 2010 – 2013 English Literature, 2:1